aap.org 2010-11-19

# AAP WEB SITE - PRIVACY STATEMENT

|    
|   
**AMERICAN ACADEMY OF PEDIATRICS** **PRIVACY STATEMENT**

The American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) takes the issue of privacy very seriously. This policy is intended to help you understand how AAP collects, uses and safeguards the information collected on our Web site. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the use or disclosure of information that is collected or obtained through means other than this Web site. 

_Collection of Information_ : Visitors may generally browse public portions of the AAP Web site anonymously without providing any personal information. However, AAP members are required to provide personal information in connection with registering for or accessing member portions of the site. In addition, personal information will be requested in connection with purchasing products or services, requesting additional information, signing up for newsletters or listservs, participating in forums or submitting questions through this site. In general, a visitor will know when personal information is being collected because he or she will have to fill out a form. AAP does not knowingly collect or use any personal information from users under 13 years of age. AAP will endeavor to correct, update or remove collected personal data if contacted (webmaster@aap.org). 

_AAP Use of Information_ : Any information collected on the Web site will be used by the AAP only for the purpose stated at the time of collection. Only those who ask to be added to AAP e-mail lists or who ask for information from AAP will receive e-mail communications from AAP. AAP members may be automatically added to AAP e-mail lists or certain other private lists if AAP has an e-mail address for the member. E-mail addresses may be removed from AAP e-mail lists at any time by following the applicable opt-out procedure specified in the list welcome message or by contacting the [AAP Listmaster](mailto:listmaster@aap.org) and specifying the name of the list. AAP may share statistical or aggregated, non-personal information about our visitors with affiliates, business partners and other third parties. This data is used for administrative purposes only. 

_Sharing of Information_ : AAP may provide personal information to third party agents that have been hired to help provide a requested good or service. For example, in connection with a product order, AAP would need to provide the collected credit card number to a payment authorization service and the corresponding address to a shipping company to deliver the package. Unless directed otherwise at the time of collection, AAP may also share collected personal information with third parties who may have information or services that AAP believes could be helpful to members or visitors. AAP may also share personally identifiable information obtained from an AAP member for the purpose of facilitating the member's access to programs and activities consistent with AAP's goal of improving quality in the delivery of pediatric health care services. AAP members may change their preference for the sharing of information on the member page. Other visitors may also opt-out from the sharing of collected information by contacting the AAP Webmaster (webmaster@aap.org). 

_Cookies and Tracking Information_ : AAP may use "cookie" technology to obtain non-personal information from its on-line visitors. AAP servers may also collect the IP addresses and domain names of visitors for site administration purposes. AAP does not extract personal information in these processes, nor does AAP provide this information to third parties. AAP does not contact on-line visitors based on information in the AAP cookie file. 

AAP has taken commercially reasonable steps to protect information received from online visitors against unauthorized access and use. All information is protected by AAP security measures, which are periodically reviewed. 

AAP reserves the right to disclose without notice to the user any information in its possession if required to do so by law, to protect or defend AAP's rights or property, or to respond to an emergency. This Web site contains links to third-party Web sites which are not under the control of the AAP. AAP is not responsible for the privacy practices of any linked site. 

AAP reserves the right to revise this privacy statement at any time by posting a revised statement on this Web site. Use of this Web site after such change signifies the user's acceptance of the changed terms. 

Specific areas or pages of this Web site may include additional or different terms relating to the use of personal information collected from such areas or pages and, in the context presented, in the event of any conflict between those specific terms and this Privacy Statement, those specific terms shall control. 

This Privacy Statement is effective as of October 21, 2005. Questions about this privacy policy or requests concerning AAP privacy practices should be directed to the AAP Webmaster (webmaster@aap.org). 

|    
|
